A Guide to the Papers of the University Librarian, bulk 1960-1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the University Librarian RG-12/1/1.031
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-12/1/1.031
This collection consists of 52 boxes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions apply to personally identifiable records pertaining to human resources and personnel in Box 52.
Acquisition Information
Archival transfer.
Scope and Content
The papers contain correspondence, reports, minutes, memoranda and printed material re the University of Virginia Library, staff and collections. During the time span of these papers Jack Dalton (1950-1956), John Cook Wyllie (1956- 1968), Ray Frantz (1968-1993) and Karin Wittenborg (1994- ) held the position of University Librarian. Topics in the subject files include the American Library Association; the Associates of the University of Virginia Library, the Association of Research Libraries, the Association of Southeastern Research Libraries, the Bibliographic Society of the University of Virginia, capital outlay, Clemons Library, collection development, computing activities, Directors' Council, emergency procedures, faculty procedures and research, goals, HEW statistics and Title II, human resources, insurance, library hours, the McGregor Library, networks, payroll, personnel, physical plant, preservation, publications, safety and security, SCHEV, Solinet, space projections, storage center, travel and Virginia State University.
Organization
Series I. Subject files, Boxes 1-38. Series II. Library gift files, Boxes 39-51. Series III. Restricted files. Box 52.
Contents List
- Series I: Subject Files
  - Administration-Vice President 1982 (Box 1)
  - American Library Association (2 folders) 1975-1980 (Box 1)
  - Associates of the University of Virginia Library (2 folders) 1982-1989 (Box 1)
  - Association of College and Research Libraries 1972-1975 (Box 1)
  - Association of College and Research Libraries-Publications in Librarianship 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Association of Research Libraries 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Association of Research Libraries (4 folders) 1977-1989 (Box 2)
  - Association of Research Libraries - Annual Salary Survey (3 folders) 1967-1985 (Box 2)
  - Association of Research Libraries - Annual Salary Survey 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Association of Research Libraries - Pilot Preservation Statistics Survey 1986 (Box 3)
  - Association of Research Libraries Statistics (5 folders) 1967-1984 (Box 3)
  - Association of Research Libraries-Statistics (2 folders) 1985-1990 (Box 4)
  - Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (3 folders) 1970, 1975-1993 (Box 4)
  - Association of Southeastern Research Libraries-Minutes 1956-1990 (Box 4)
  - Association of Southeastern Research Libraries-Statistics (3 folders) 1957-1996 (Box 5)
  - Audiovisual 1987-1989 (Box 5)
  - Bibliographic Society of the University of Virginia (2 folders) 1980-1992 (Box 5)
  - Binding 1983-1990 (Box 5)
  - Blandy Farm 1985 (Box 5)
  - Board of Alderman 1980-1990 (Box 5)
  - Calendar 1984-1990 (Box 5)
  - Canadian Materials 1984 (Box 5)
  - Capital Outlay (3 folders) 1980-1986 (Box 6)
  - Center for Research Libraries 1980-1992 (Box 6)
  - Clemons Library (2 folders) 1980-1981 May (Box 6)
  - Clemons Library (2 folders) 1981 (Box 7)
  - Collections Development (6 folders) 1980-1985 (Box 7)
  - Collections Development 1986-1988 Jul (Box 8)
  - Collections Development 1988 Aug-1989 (Box 9)
  - Collections Development 1995 (Box 9)
  - Collections Development Bibliography 1980-1984 (Box 9)
  - Colonnade Club 1980 (Box 10)
  - Comptroller (2 folders) 1980-1989 (Box 10)
  - Computing Activities (4 folders) 1983-1986 Mar (Box 10)
  - Computing Activities (6 folders) 1986 Apr-1987 Oct (Box 11)
  - Computing Activities (7 folders) 1987 Dec-1989 Jul (Box 12)
  - Computing Activities (7 folders) 1989 Aug-Dec (Box 13)
  - Copyright 1980-1985 (Box 13)
  - Council of Higher Education 1986-1989 (Box 13)
  - Department of Libraries-Health Sciences 1980-1988 (Box 13)
  - Department of Religious Studies 1968-1976 (Box 13)
  - Director's Council 1989 (Box 13)
  - Director's Council Minutes (5 folders) 1979-1988 (Box 14)
  - Document Delivery (2 folders) 1987-1989 (Box 14)
  - Emergency Procedures (2 folders) 1980-1999 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1980-1984 (Box 15)
  - Faculty Procedures (2 folders) 1987 (Box 15)
  - Faculty Research (2 folders) 1983-1986 (Box 15)
  - Faculty Senate Committee 1976-1987 (Box 15)
  - Gifts 1985-1988 (Box 16)
  - Goals (1 of 3) 1986-1990 (Box 16)
  - Goals and Objectives 1981-1985 (Box 16)
  - Goals-Biennial Evaluation and Planning Report 1984-1998 (Box 16)
  - Government Documents 1986-1990 (Box 16)
  - Handicapped 1975-1989 (Box 17)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW) Department 1969-1988 (Box 17)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW) Statistics (2 folders) 1969-1979 (Box 17)
  - Hew Statistics 1977-1978 (Box 17)
  - Hew-Title II 1977-1980 (Box 17)
  - Hew-Title II, IIA (4 folders) 1966-1976 (Box 18)
  - History Department 1975-1985 (Box 18)
  - Honor Committee 1975-1978 (Box 18)
  - Human Resources-Benefits 1981-1989 (Box 18)
  - Human Resources - Community Service 1988 (Box 18)
  - Human Resources-Employee Education 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Human Resources-Employee Work Injury 1988 (Box 18)
  - Human Resources-Equal Opportunity Program 1981 (Box 18)
  - Human Resources-Hiring Procedure 1982-1989 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Immigration 1986-1990 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Merit Increases 1983-1985 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Requests for Faculty 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Salaries 1988-1989 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Salaries (Hourly Pay Rates) 1981-1989 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Schedules 1981-1989 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Service Awards 1987-1989 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Service Ratings 1972-1988 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Staff Development 1984-1989 (Box 19)
  - Human Resources-Staffing 1968-1997 (Box 20)
  - Human Resources - Student Assistants 1988-1989 (Box 20)
  - Human Resources-Time and Attendance 1967-1989 (Box 20)
  - Human Resources-Workers' Compensation 1988-1990 (Box 20)
  - Information Services (2 folders) 1982-1996 (Box 20)
  - Institutional Analysis (Mr. Frank Lankforg) 1980-1986 (Box 20)
  - Insurance (2 folders) 1980-1989 (Box 20)
  - International Federation of Library Associations and Institutions 1987-1989 (Box 21)
  - Library Hours (2 folders) 1980-1994 (Box 21)
  - Materials Organization 1988-1989 (Box 21)
  - McGregor Library (3 folders) 1960-1989 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous 1976-1989 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous A 1977-1978 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous H 1976-1991 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous K 1985 (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous S 1977-1989 (Box 22)
  - Networks (3 folders) 1981-1990 (Box 22)
  - Optical Disk 1983 (Box 22)
  - Parking and Transportation 1976-1989 (Box 22)
  - Payroll (2 folders) 1975-1989 (Box 22)
  - Personnel 1981, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Personnel-Equal Opportunity Program 1982-1989 (Box 23)
  - Personnel-Fair Labor Standards Act 1981 (Box 23)
  - Personnel-Grievance Procedure 1981 (Box 23)
  - Personnel-Half Time Positions 1981 (Box 23)
  - Personnel-Leave (3 folders) 1981-1985 (Box 23)
  - Personnel-Positions Descriptions 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Personnel - Service Awards 1981-1986 (Box 23)
  - Personnel - state Classified Procedures 1981-1984 (Box 23)
  - Personnel-Student Assistants 1981-1987 (Box 23)
  - Personnel-Time-Income Tradeoff 1984-1986 (Box 24)
  - Physical Plant (5 folders) 1976-1989 (Box 24)
  - Preservation (2 folders) 1981 Jan-Sep (Box 24)
  - Preservation (7 folders) 1981 Oct-1985 Jul (Box 25)
  - Preservation (5 folders) 1985 Aug-1989 (Box 26)
  - President's Office 1975-1993 (Box 26)
  - Program Evaluation 1982 (Box 26)
  - Program Evaluation (5 folders) 1983-2000 (Box 27)
  - Promotional Review Board 1985-1999 (Box 27)
  - Provost 1982-1989 (Box 27)
  - Publications 1986-1990 (Box 28)
  - Publications of Library Staff Members 1959-1978 (Box 28)
  - Publications Committee and Related - Funding (2 folders) 1977-1987 (Box 28)
  - Questionnaires (3 folders) 1980-1989 (Box 28)
  - Rare Books and Manuscripts-Security 1974-1976 (Box 28)
  - Research Grants 1968-1990 (Box 29)
  - Resources Distribution (2 folders) 1988-1992 (Box 29)
  - Retrospective Conversion 1981-1984 (Box 29)
  - Rotation 1989 (Box 29)
  - Safety (2 folders) 1973-1988 (Box 29)
  - Safety 1999 (Box 29)
  - Science Library Advisory Committee 1980 (Box 29)
  - Security 1980-1982 (Box 29)
  - Security (2 folders) 1983-1989 (Box 30)
  - Serials Section 1982-1986 (Box 30)
  - Serials Section (2 folders) 1989 (Box 30)
  - Shelf List 1980-1989 (Box 30)
  - Shelf Study 1980-1989 (Box 31)
  - Signs 1980-1987 (Box 31)
  - Size of Collections (2 folders) 1957-1989 (Box 31)
  - Slavic 1981-1988 (Box 31)
  - Smoking 1987-1989 (Box 31)
  - Solinet (2 folders) 1979-1994 (Box 31)
  - Space Projections (3 folders) 1972-1985 (Box 32)
  - Space Projects 1986-1990 (Box 32)
  - Space Projections-Alderman Library (3 folders) 1975-1984 (Box 32)
  - Space Projections-Alderman Library 1985-1990 (Box 33)
  - Special Collections 1983-1989 (Box 33)
  - Speech Department 1982 (Box 33)
  - Sponsored Programs 1980-1990 (Box 33)
  - Staff Association 1990-1994 (Box 33)
  - Staff Members (list) 1980-1982 (Box 33)
  - State Council of Higher Education in Virginia (SCHEV) 1980-1989 (Box 33)
  - State Council of Higher Education in Virginia/PEDS: Statistics 1980-1985 (Box 33)
  - Storage Center (2 folders) 1974-1987 (Box 33)
  - Storage Center (2 folders) 1987-1989 (Box 34)
  - Telephones 1980-1986 (Box 34)
  - Telephones 1987-1989 (Box 35)
  - Title II (6 folders) 1980-1985 (Box 35)
  - Title II 1989 (Box 36)
  - Travel (3 folders) 1980-1989 (Box 36)
  - University Library Committee (3 folders) 1980-1985 (Box 36)
  - University Library Committee 1985-1989 (Box 37)
  - University Library Committee-Subcommittee on Collection Development Policies 1980-1987 (Box 37)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University 1980-1983 (Box 37)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University 1984-1988 (Box 38)
  - Virginia State University (5 folders) 1980-1992 (Box 38)
- Series II: Library Gift Files
  - Library Gift Files 1951-1975 (Box 39)
  - Library Gift Files: A-Am 1968-1977 (Box 39)
  - Library Gift Files: A-L (3 folders) 1978 (Box 39)
  - Library Gift Files: Alderman Gifts 1974-1975 (Box 39)
  - Library Gift Files: A-N 1979 (Box 39)
  - Library Gift Files: A-N 1979 (Box 40)
  - Library Gift Files: An-Az 1968-1977 (Box 40)
  - Library Gift Files: A-Z 1977 (Box 40)
  - Library Gift Files: B-Ba 1968-1977 (Box 40)
  - Library Gift Files: Be-Bish 1968-1977 (Box 40)
  - Library Gift Files: Bisi-Bp 1968-1977 (Box 40)
  - Library Gift Files: Board of Visitors 1952-1968 (Box 41)
  - Library Gift Files: Board of Visitors Gift Books (3 folders) 1970-1978 (Box 41)
  - Library Gift Files: Board of Visitors Gift Books A-Z 1978-1979 (Box 41)
  - Library Gift Files: Board of Visitors Gift Forms 1982-1983 (Box 41)
  - Library Gift Files: Board of Visitors Monetary Gifts 1975-1979 (Box 42)
  - Library Gift Files: Board of Visitors Monetary Gifts A-Z 1974-1975 (Box 42)
  - Library Gift Files: Board of Visitors Monetary Gifts A-Z 1968-1974 (Box 42)
  - Library Gift Files: Board of Visitors Reports Gift Books A-Z 1974-1975 (Box 42)
  - Library Gift Files: Br-Bz 1968-1977 (Box 42)
  - Library Gift Files: C-Ca 1968-1977 (Box 43)
  - Library Gift Files: Ce-Cn 1968-1977 (Box 43)
  - Library Gift Files: Co-Cz 1-968-1977 (Box 43)
  - Library Gift Files: D-Da 1968-1977 (Box 43)
  - Library Gift Files: Db-Dp 1968-1977 (Box 44)
  - Library Gift Files: Dr-Dz 1968-1977 (Box 44)
  - Library Gift Files: Dr. Halmen List 1942-1945 (Box 44)
  - Library Gift Files: E 1968-1977 (Box 44)
  - Library Gift Files: F 1968-1977 (Box 44)
  - Library Gift Files: Far Places Collection 1939-1960 (Box 45)
  - Library Gift Files: Ga-Gk 1968-1977 (Box 45)
  - Library Gift Files: Gl-Gz 1968-1977 (Box 45)
  - Library Gift Files: H-Haz 1968-1977 (Box 45)
  - Library Gift Files: Hb-Hz (2 folders) 1968-1977 (Box 45)
  - Library Gift Files: I 1968-1977 (Box 46)
  - Library Gift Files: J 1968-1977 (Box 46)
  - Library Gift Files: James Adams Taylor 1957-1958 (Box 46)
  - Library Gift Files: K 1968-1977 (Box 46)
  - Library Gift Files: L (2 folders) 1968-1977 (Box 46)
  - Library Gift Files: Library of Dr. Laurence T. Royster 1953 (Box 46)
  - Library Gift Files: L-Z (2 folders) 1978 (Box 47)
  - Library Gift Files M-Mac (3 folders) 1968-1977 (Box 47)
  - Library Gift Files: Mas-May 1968-1977 (Box 47)
  - Library Gift Files: Mea-Mz 1968-1977 (Box 48)
  - Library Gift Files: Miscellaneous 1950-1951 (Box 48)
  - Library Gift Files: N-Nea 1968-1977 (Box 48)
  - Library Gift Files: Neb-Nz 1968-1977 (Box 48)
  - Library Gift Files: O 1968-1977 (Box 48)
  - Library Gift Files: O-Z 1979 (Box 48)
  - Library Gift Files: O-Z 1979 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: Past Months Unfiled 1968 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: P-Pez 1968-1977 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: Pf-Pz 1968-1977 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: Policy Memo 1969 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: Q 1968-1977 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: R-Riz 1968-1977 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: Rj-Rz 1968-1977 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: S-Sh 1968-1977 (Box 49)
  - Library Gift Files: S-Sh 1968-1977 (Box 50)
  - Library Gift Files: Si-So 1968-1980 (Box 50)
  - Library Gift Files: Sp-Sz 1960-1980 (Box 50)
  - Library Gift Files: T-Taz 1968-1980 (Box 50)
  - Library Gift Files: Tb-Tz (2 folders) 1968-1980 (Box 50)
  - Library Gift Files: U 1968-1980 (Box 51)
  - Library Gift Files: V (2 folders) 1960-1981 (Box 51)
  - Library Gift Files: W-Wh 1968-1980 (Box 51)
  - Library Gift Files: Wi-Wz 1968-1980 (Box 51)
  - Library Gift Files: X, Y, Z 1968-1980 (Box 51)
- SERIES III: RESTRICTED FILES
  - Disaster and Accident Reports (2 folders) 1981-1989 (Box 52)
  - Emergency Procedures - Incident Report 1980-1999 (Box 52)
  - Human Resources-Employee Suggestion Program 1985 (Box 52)
  - Human Resources-Records 1980-1988 (Box 52)
  - Human Resources - Time and Attendance 1967-1969 (Box 52)
  - Human Resources - Workers Compensation Cases 1988-1990 (Box 52)
  - Personnel-Volunteers 1988-1989 (Box 52)
  - Personnel - Special Collections - Sick Leave 1988 (Box 52)